

AVINASH DHUMAL

ASSOCIATE MANAGER - IT

CONTACT INFO



+91-779-840-6759



avinash_dhumal@yahoo.com

ΩŮ

Pune, MH, India

ONLINE PRESENCE



LinkedIn Profile



Online Profile



Oll medium.com blog



Hacker Rank Profile

ABOUT ME

Technical people leader with 11.8+ years of software architect, design, development, management, and support experience using Azure & AWS Cloud infrastructures. Developed, managed, and led client, database, and enterprise applications/products on Microsoft Azure, AWS Cloud and Non-Cloud platforms with Microsoft Technology stack. Currently working as Tech Manager and designated as Associate Manager at Pitney Bowes, Inc. and managing & leading global mailing products called Tier3 & DLA.

EXPERIENCE

ASSOCIATE MANAGER - IT PITNEY BOWES, INC. FEB 2020 - CURRENT



- Leading and managing Tier3 and DLA product operations and automations for global markets.
- Playing a vital role in leading and architecting PBots Self Service portal for automating operational activities.
- Leading and managing T3Online web product development in agile methodologies.
- Playing important role in handling application & server specific vulnerability. Successfully improved Horizon Rapid 7 security score from 10+ to 1+.
- Took the charge of managing on premise to AWS migration (completed 18+ countries).
- Currently managing & leading a team of 10 engineers (direct report) and responsible for their KRA, annual goals and performance appraisals and mentoring.

ASSISTANT MANAGER - IT FLEX



JUN 2015 - FEB 2020

- Delivered 3 major releases and more than 50+ sprints successfully on production over a span of 4.5 years.
- Successfully led automated order processing (EDI) worth revenue of ~10 million dollars.
- Managed major release (FY 2018-19) & achieved more than ~110 million-dollar ROI.
- Played scrum master role and managed a team of 6 people (direct report) and driven projects in AGILE methodology using Azure DevOps and was responsible for their KRA, annual goals, performance appraisals and mentoring.

SKILLS

.NET .NET MVC C# Core VB.NET Web API SQL Windows Server Services WCF Web HTML5/ Bootstrap Services CSS3 2-3-4 jQuery Angular Angular TypeScript JS 11-13

— TOOLS	;		
1002	•		
TFS	GitLab	Jira	Azure DevOps
Service Now	Remedy	Pager Duty	Jenkins
MS Projects	MS Visio	Wireframe Sketcher	Lucid Charts
Checkmarx	Confluence		

CLOUD PLATFORMS

Azure AWS

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER (LEAD) L&T INFOTECH

LT1

MAY 2014 - JUN 2015

- Involved in collecting requirements for Elevator business and led & designed electronic service dashboard for Otis Elevator customers using ASP.NET, VB.NET and SQL Server 2012, HTML 5, jQuery, bootstrap, CSS3.
- Documented requirement provided by end customers and designed wireframes, functional specs to finalize UI design and system requirement specifications.
- Driven Performance tuning and UAT testing with stakeholders.
- Led a team of 12 people. (10 Developers & 2 Testers)

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER HEXAWARE TECHNOLOGIES DEC 2010 - MAY 2014



- Successfully provided production support for AMPS products for the client EY.
- Successfully automated functional/core processes to support critical business requirements of Identity and Access Management domain.
- Designed application code to support end user requirement/business requirement using ASP.NET, C#, SQL Server 2010, ¡Query, CSS.
- Assisted in the research, analysis, problems, and coordination of department staff.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering - I.T.

Diploma - I.T.

Pune University

MSBTE, Mumbai

JULY 2010

JUNE 2007

65.13 %

70.17 %

S. S. C.

Pune Vidyapeeth

JUNE 2004

72.80 %

PROJECT 1

TIER3, DLA, T3ONLINE, AWS CLOUD MIGRATION & VULNERABILITY ASSESSMENT PITNEY BOWES, INC.



2020 - CURRENT

- Responsible for leading and managing Tier3 and DLA product operations and automations for global markets.
- Responsible for implementing ITIL processes for smooth operations.
- Responsible for leading and architecting PBots Self Service portal for automating operational activities.
- Responsible for leading and managing T3Online product development in agile methodologies.
- Responsible for handling application & server specific vulnerability. (Internal and external)
- Managing On Prem to AWS migration which includes estimation, planning, forecasting, and reporting. (Completed 18+ countries)
- Currently managing & leading a team of 10 people (direct report) and responsible for their KRA, annual goals and performance appraisals.

TECHNOLOGIES
ASP.NET Core, ASP.NET MVC, C#.NET, Web API, SQL Server 2019, Windows Services, Web Services, WCF, Bootstrap 4.0, Angular 4, TypeScript, jQuery, HTML5/CSS3
MANAGERIAL SKILLS
Resource Planning, forecasting & allocation, OKRs, SWOT Analysis, Conflict Management, Risk Assessment, Reporting, Strategic Talent Review (Quarterly) with Director and India HR Head.
FAMILIAR
MS Projects, MS Visio, Jira, Confluence, TFS, GitLab, Remedy, Dynatrace, PagerDuty, Checkmarx, Jenkins, Ansible, Terraforms, CI-CD, AWS - EC2, Fargate, Container Services, S3 Bucket, Backups, Vaults, CloudWatch, MGN Service, Cloud Endure, Lambda Function, Athena, SMS Service, VPC, Subnets, Security

PROJECT 2

COMMAND CENTER FLEX



2015 - 2020

Policies

- Played agile scrum master role and responsible for solution architect and delivery of the product by leveraging Azure DevOps & CI/CD pipeline.
- Involved in requirement gathering to collect Supply Chain Management business.
- Delivered 3 major releases and more than 50+ sprints successfully on production over a span of 4.5 years.
- Successfully led automated order processing (EDI) worth revenue of ~10 million dollars.
- Managed major release (FY 2018-19) & achieved more than ~110 million-dollar ROI.
- Developed applications in .NET stack and on Azure platform.
- Played scrum master role and managed a team of 6 people (direct report) and driven projects in AGILE methodology using Azure DevOps and was responsible for their KRA, annual goals and appraisals.

TECHNOLOGIES ————
ASP.NET MVC, C#.NET, SQL Server 2019, Bootstrap 4.0, Angular 13, TypeScript, jQuery, HTML5/CSS3
MANAGERIAL SKILLS
Scrum Master, Resource Planning, forecasting & allocation, OKRs, SWOT Analysis, Conflict Management, Risk Assessment, Reporting
FAMILIAR
TFS, Azure DevOps, CI-CD, Checkmarx, MS Visio, ServiceNow, Azure - Web Roles, Worker Roles, Web Apps, Azure Functions, Blob, Queues, Tables

PROJECT 3

ESERVICE 2.0 L&T Infotech 2014 - 2015



- Involved in requirement gathering to collect/understand Elevator business.
- Documented new requirements provided by end customers and designing draft sketches to finalize UI design for the end customer.
- Designed and maintained application code to support end user requirements.
- Assisted with the technical and functional knowledge of the team during the development and/or maintenance of the software product.
- Effectively handled client calls/issues irrespective of geographic Locations.
- Managed & Led team of 12 people for redesign project.

TECHNOLOGIES		
ASP.NET MVC, C#.NET, VB.NET, SQL Server 2012, Bootstrap 2.0, jQuery, HTML5/CSS3		
MANAGERIAL SKILLS		
Scrum Master, Resource Planning, forecasting & allocation, Risk Assessment, Reporting		
FAMILIAR —		
TFS, MS Visio, Wireframes, Lucid		

PROJECT 4

AMPS (Account Management & Provisioning System) Hexaware Technologies



2010 - 2014

- Successfully implemented interface programs to interact with other platforms and enhance overall functionality of an application.
- Successfully automated core functionality of an application to support business critical aspects.
- Designed SQL scripts to automated workflow which reduced overall cost of resolution and SLA agreed.
- Resolved end user queries/issues in Application at L3/L4 level within defined SLAs.

	TECHNOLOGIES	
ASP.NET, C#.NET, SQL Server 2012		
	FAMILIAR ————	
TFS, Remedy, ERT, ORT, ITIL Processes, Outage handling		

AWARDS

	AWARDS		
	DECEMBER 2021	Ace Award	Pitney Bowes, Inc.
		Leading and effectively managing Tier3 AWS migration and innovating automation tools.	
	MARCH 2021	Star Award	Pitney Bowes, Inc.
	2021	Leading and effectively managing Tier3 and DLA product operations & team and taking smooth hand over of knowledge transition from vendor.	
	FEBRUARY 2018	Gateway – The leaders League	flex
	2016	Leadership Training Program (6 months program)	
	OCTOBER 2017	Titanium Award	flex
	2017	Designed a self-service web portal and automated all production cases for quicker response. Reduced overall MTR.	
	SEPTEMBER 2016	Platinum Award	flex
		Designed SQL Deployment Tool for automatic SQL deployments.	
	AUGUST 2014	Spot Award	L&T Infotech
		For quick understanding of OTIS elevators business and designing outstanding functional requirement specifications.	
	SEPTEMBER 2012	Ace Award	Hexaware Technologies
	7 *	For effectively handling AMPS production support applications and clients.	